

Thishan Rasangika

Support Operations Engineer - L2

+947-1288-9972

thishan.rasangika@gmail.com 🔀

linkedin.com/in/thishanr/ in



About Me

Challenging position in a dynamic and growth-oriented organization where I can utilize my practical experience and skills to achieve both personal and professional growth. I am committed to bringing a positive and driven approach to my work and contributing to the success of the company. I seek stability and opportunities for career advancement, and am excited to join a professional team that values innovation and excellence.

Certification

Successfully earned a certificate in Administering Active Directory Domain Services

https://lnkd.in/dAmHkSe5

Technical Skills

- Problem Solving & Strong Analytical skills
- Experience in Azure AD and on- premise AD, Exchange (online/on premise) and o365
- Experience in ITIL v4
- Experience in ITSM System (ServiceNow, ManageEngine)
- Experience in PowerShell Scripting

Expertise

- **End User Support**
- **Engineers Training**
- SOP Handling
- User Flows
- Leadership
- Effective Team Management

Work Experience

2020 -Current Senior Infra. Analyst | HCLT Lan. (Pvt) Ltd.

Responsibilities

- · As the lead for Identity and Access Management (IAM) within the DWP, I am responsible as Domain admin, gathering requirements and managing customers' infrastructure and servers for Microsoft Entra ID, Directory Synchronization, Exchange, Microsoft Active Directory, and Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA)
- · Keeping track and regularly upgrading the OS and Service versions of IAM servers/Services with the coordination of multiple teams
- · Managing the Team members working at different locations for driving all DWP and project-related activities under IAM.
- Managing the active directory/ Exchange, Users, Groups, Conditional Access Policies etc. microsoft active directory, along with the regular clean-ups of the
- · Building the Infrastructure Documents (Runbook, Design Document etc.) for IAM Services.
- Building the "Understanding and Troubleshooting" Documents for the support team
- · Getting to the core of the issues and understanding the root cause to fix the bulk incidents in one go
- Internal trainer for the Level 02 support engineers guiding them related to Entra ID, Microsoft active directory (First ever Sri Lanka HCLT T2ID Trainer)
- Ensure Simplify, Standardize, Rationalize and 'Fix First', 'Team of Teams' mindset
- Driving changes AD site level changes, DNS, DHCP, GPO-related changes
- Ensure Happy customer, Customer first and can do, mindset
- Responsible person for OneDrive migration process, withing OneDrive migration process I'm taken care of user data. It's beneficial for the company because all users' data is more valuable, without any data loss OneDrive migration saving time and valuable user data
- Microsoft active directory Implementation and administration
- Administration & Troubleshooting of 2012 R2, 2016, 2019, 2022 Exchange Servers
- Domain Controller health review using some batch scripts
- Active Directory replication monitoring & Trouble shooting the replication issues
- Group Policy administration
- · Managing of DNS, DHCP resource records
- Perform Windows Servers patch managements on Every month using Big fix & Windows catalog
- Diagnose and troubleshooting of DNS name resolution issues and DHCP
- Users and group creation/deletion in Entra ID environment

Work Experience

2018 -2019 IT Executive | Srikon Tours (Pvt) Ltd.

Responsibilities

- Creation of SOP & Service Management documents
- Web Development and IT Infrastructure Support
- Google workplace Support
- Printer configuration and Setup

2017 -2018 Trainee Software Engineer (WEB) | Bhasha Lanka (Pvt) Ltd.

Responsibilities

- · Maintaining the internal Apps API, creation and ensure API security for business continuity.
- · Can do mind set and collaboration with internal team
- · work with the limited time duration
- handling the technology such as PHP, MySQL, Codeigniter, Bootstrap, Ajex and Json

2019 -2024 IT Infrastructure Support (Freelance) | Miriswaththa Nenasala Edu. Center.

Responsibilities

- Creation of SOP & Service Management documents
- Maintaining IT Infrastructure for Nenasala Miriswaththa including Web development
- Site integration with security Maintaining and implementation
- DNS and Couldfare Management

Education

Bachelor of Sciences (Hons) in Computing

Graduated BSc (Hons) in Computing with Second Upper Class awarded by Wrexham Glyndŵr University, UK at 2020 September

Higher Diploma in Computer Systems Engineering

Graduated Higher Diploma in Computer Systems Engineering with Distinction awarded by Londontec City Campus LK at 2019 August

Diploma in English

Graduated Diploma in English with Distinction awarded by Nenasala Miriswaththa LK at 2020 February

NAITA Six Month Industrial Training with Diploma in IT

Graduated Diploma in IT with National Apprentice and Industrial Training Authority Six Month Industrial Training Sri Lanka Institute of Advanced Technological Education, (SLIATE) LK 2019 November

Reference

Mr. Anshu Middha

Senior AD/M365 Engineer| Bekaert

Phone: +91 850 580 0071 **Email:** Anshu2630@gmail.com

Mr. Seraj Ali

Technical Specialist | HCL Technologies

Phone: +91 965 038 2525

Email: serajtauheed@gmail.com

Declaration

I hereby certify that, this resume correctly describes me, my qualifications and my experience to the best of my knowledge and belief

my knowledge and belief

Signature: Thishan Rasangika (Thishan.rasangika@gmail.com)

Page 2 of 2